Obinna Okonkwo

ObinnaOkonkwo1@outlook.com • (240) 584-9193 • Linkedln

CAREER PROFILE

Data-driven, Business Analyst with a Master's in Information Technology and 2+ years of experience conducting in-depth analysis for business optimization projects while identifying creative solutions to complex business problems. Polished in formulating process improvement strategies and overseeing new technology and system implementation. Commercially-aware professional equipped with strong project management, interpersonal skills and technical knowledge of computing systems. Solid SQL query writing skills paired with familiarity of visualization tools and techniques.

EDUCATION

University of Maryland, Global Campus Largo, MD

December 2021

Master of Science | Majors: Information Technology

GPA: 3.6

Howard University, Washington D.C.

May 2018

Bachelor of Science | Majors: Electrical Engineering

Certifications

- PCEP Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer | Python Institute | 2021
- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate | Google | 2021
- Certified ScrumMaster Certification | Scrum Alliance (In Progress)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Avior Strategies Inc, Arlington, VA

May 2022 - Present

Business Analyst

- Implemented a modification in existing workflow that yielded a 15% decrease in helpdesk tickets from partner agency
- Redesigned and streamlined existing onboarding process by constructing new employee wiki which reduced onboarding by a minimum of 14 days subsequently reducing operational costs for the organization
- Collaborated directly alongside Senior Analyst to gather, document, and maintain requirements while providing technical support and solutions to internal and external partners enhancing their agency's performance
- Investigated gaps and developed test conditions to validate business requirements. Executed UAT scripts and completed
 problem logs and participated in resolution/retest of issues optimizing business processes
- Partnered with the engineering team to contribute, prioritize, and deliver on the roadmap for a feature while adhering to performance requirements and standards throughout the development lifecycle

Helpdesk Analyst

- Promoted to Business Analyst after reducing end user tickets by 20% through proactive issue identification and resolution
- Spearheaded & applied enhancements and reformations utilizing improved troubleshooting techniques and issue tracking which subsequently increased first call resolution rates from 60% to 85%
- Utilized effective problem solving technique and efficient workflows which reduced the average time to close a ticket by 25%

Bozzuto Development Company, Arlington, VA

2019-2022

Technical Assistant

- Enhanced departmental efficiency and reduced call volume at Help Desk by 50% through the implementation of a self-service knowledge base
- Processed and tracked service requests and created service tickets in the help desk software
- Investigate and resolve hardware and software problems and perform basic hardware and software maintenance including regularly scheduled backups and preventative maintenance.
- Contributed to a renewal rate of 20% in lease renewals and Customer Attraction and Happiness noted by 5-star Yelp reviews
- Maximized efficiency by closing tickets under 48 hours while assisting Maintenance/Contractors in communicating with residents

T.A.G Labs Inc. 2017-2019

Business Analyst Intern

- Translated business user concepts and ideas into comprehensive business requirements and design documents
- Planned, facilitated, and reported on quality assurance testing efforts
- Reviewed business priorities, and analyzed options, risks, and costs

Helpdesk Analyst Intern

- Promoted to Business Analyst role after showcasing strong team collaboration skills, while maintaining departmental goals
 and accurately diagnosing and problem-solving system, hardware, and software problems followed by documenting issues
- Maintained IT equipment inventory with periodic audits and cleanup
- Configured system set-ups and ensure network connectivity, installed and tested hardware and software

Projects - System Analysis & Design Capstone Project

Memory Magic App - Project Management

- Developed an application module and interface that would allow speech-to-text capability, to assist those with dementia. As
 the role of Project Manager, this project allowed me to understand the SDLC of a short-term software project and to
 effectively communicate project scope, schedule, and budget with both customers and contractors
- Full report included Business case, Risk Management Plan, Testing, System Architecture, Process Management, System Specs,
 User Experience, Prep for Implementation & Deployment, and Retrospective

SKILLS & RELATED COURSEWORK

Skills:

- Programming: Python, SQL, HTML/CSS/Bootstrap
- Software: Docker, MS Office Suite, Evolus Pencil, Visual Studio, Tableau, Power BI, Jupyter, Adobe Creative Cloud, Oracle DB 12c
- CRMs: Salesforce, Yardi
- Project Management tools: Trello, Jira, ClickUP
- Platforms: Windows, MacOS, iOS, Android
- Technical Skills: Data Analysis, Project Management, Agile, Software/API Testing, Scrum

Government Security Clearance:

Public Trust – Completed 2022

Related Coursework:

- System Analysis & Design: Managed projects identifying user needs and applied logical approaches to find creative solutions using design thinking
- Production & Ops Mgmt: Learned to balance multiple tasks and meet deadlines in manufacturing environments
- Data Analytics for Enterprises: Managed group projects where we analyzed data to supported final decisions